Contact

Indianapolis, IN 3174423712 (Mobile) chrsrn6@me.com

www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-k-a4a43b61 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Hospitals Wound Care

Languages English

Christopher Kinnaird RN

Registered Nurse

Fortville, Indiana

Summary

Registered Nurse with background in homecare nursing of all ages and neonatal nursing.

Have worked in the home care field for the last 13 Years and worked in NICU before that. Experience in all aspects of home care including IV Infusions, all aspects of wound care and broad area of wound care treatments, Including wound vacs. Experience with ng/peg/g/j tube enteral feedings. Oasis documentation, PICC/ Port/Central Line/Pheresis Catheter/Hickman/Peripheral Line care. Influson Catheters, Venipuncture, In-Ratio testing for PT/ INR's, diabetic management and education, CHF management and education. COPD education, Use of multiple IV/Enteral Pumps such as CADD, Curlin, Med Fusion, Elastomeric, Accu flo, Kangaroo, Joey, eclipse. JP Drain care, Pleurx Drains, Pin Rose Drains, Hepatic Drains, GI Drains, ostomies, colostomy, illeostomy, Nephrostomy, Urostomy, S/P Catheters, Foley Catheters, irrigation of catheters, Trach care, suctioning of trach, general/ head to toe assessments of adults, adolescents, toddlers, and infants. Respiratory treatments, IM, SQ, Injections. Education and monitoring of Oxygen, CPAP, BIPAP, Vents

Experience

Indiana University Health

11 years

IV/PEDS RN

September 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months)

indianapolis, indiana area

Nurse for all IV patients and all pediatric patients that go home from the hospital with home care.

Registered Nurse

August 2009 - Present (11 years)

Indianapolis, Indiana, United States

St Vincent's Health Home Care Nurse January 2012 - June 2020 (8 years 6 months) Indianapolis, Indiana

Case manager for homecare patients. Performing wound care, Wound vac dressing changes, Ostomy care, Catheter insertions for Foley's and S/P Catheters, IV infusions, Labs, central line/port/PIV/PICC line care and dressing changes. Education on CHF, Diabetes, COPD, Enteral Feedings, IV Infusions, Sub Q injections, IM injections, Medications, O2 Safety, safety in the home, fall prevention, and several other areas.

St Francis Home Care Rn Case Manager January 2003 - September 2010 (7 years 9 months)

RN Case Manager in the home care setting. Seeing patient's for several different issues such as wounds, IV Infusions, G-Tube/J-Tube Feeds PICC Line/Central Line/Port Care, Labs, Education on meds, Diabetes, CHF, Hypertension, COPD, MRSA, VRE, CDIFF, Fall Precautions, Nutritional Guidelines, Head to Toe Assessments, IVIG Infusions, Peripheral IV starts, Lymphedema treatments, Compression wrappings, Foley/Suprapubic Catheter Changes, Colostomy/Ileostomy Care and application of several various types of bags, Urostomy Care and application of Urostomy bags of several various types, Fistula Care and Application of several types of Fistula Bags, Wound Vac Dressing Changes, JP Drain Care, Staple Removal/Suture Removal, Pleurx Drain Procedure and sterile dressing changes, several other types of drain care.

IU Health Special Care Nursery RN

January 1999 - January 2003 (4 years 1 month)

Taking care of pre-mature infants, NG Feedings, Labs, IV's for fluid administration, Antibiotics, TPN, Steroids, Etc... Assessments of infants, High risk deliveries, Bili Lights/Photo therapy, Education on caring for infant and specific tasks such as Central line dressing changes, Line care, G-Tube/J-Tube/NG Tube Feedings, Education on IV infusions, Breast Feeding, Circ Care, Etc...

United States Air Force
Transportation
August 1988 - November 1992 (4 years 4 months)

Eglin Air Force Base, Florida, United States

3205 Trans Squadron

Education

Indiana University Bloomington
Associate's Degree, Science of Nursing · (1995 - 1999)